<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Committees on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Committees on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:52 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance Committee</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/finance-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/finance-committee/</guid>
      <description>The chair shall appoint a Finance Committee composed of the Treasurer and two other members promptly after the annual meeting. This committee shall prepare a budget for the administrative year and submit it to the Corporation on or before the day of the first regular meeting. This committee may from time to time submit amendments to the budget for the current administrative year, which may be adopted by a majority vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditing Committee</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/auditing-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/auditing-committee/</guid>
      <description>The chair shall appoint an Auditing Committee of three members at a regular meeting prior to the annual meeting, whose duty it shall be to audit the Treasurer’s accounts at the close of the administrative year and to report at the annual meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Committees</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/other-committees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/other-committees/</guid>
      <description>The Corporation may establish other committees, standing or special, as it shall from time to time deem necessary to carry on the work of the Corporation. The chair shall appoint their members, except that in the absence of the chair, the Board of Directors may appoint the members of a special committee, who shall be treated as though appointed by the chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ex Officio Committee Membership</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/ex-officio-committee-membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/ex-officio-committee-membership/</guid>
      <description>The chair shall be ex officio a member of all committees except the Nominating Committee and all disciplinary committees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>