<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Officers on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Officers on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 22:11:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Officers and Duties</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/officers-and-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/officers-and-duties/</guid>
      <description>The officers of the Corporation shall be a Board Chairperson; a Secretary; a Treasurer; no fewer than two and as many as twenty-two Directors; plus any and all Honorary Officers. These officers shall perform the duties prescribed by these bylaws and by the parliamentary authority adopted by the Corporation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Chairperson</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/board-chairperson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/board-chairperson/</guid>
      <description>If the office of Board Chairperson should become vacant between elections, then the Secretary shall preside until the immediate election of a chairperson pro tem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasurer</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/treasurer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/treasurer/</guid>
      <description>The Treasurer may not be related by blood, marriage, or domestic partnership within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity to any officer of the Corporation or corporate staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ex Officio Officers</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ex-officio-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ex-officio-officers/</guid>
      <description>The following persons shall be ex officio members of the Board of Directors:
 The pastor of the Local Church The district superintendent in jurisdiction of the Local Church The Regional Director of Nazarene Compassionate Ministries The President of Olivet Nazarene University The Mayor of the City of Chicago The aldermen of any and all wards of the City of Chicago whose boundaries lie within the Loop The commissioners of any and all districts of Cook County whose boundaries lie within the Loop  Except for the pastor of the Local Church, no ex officio member may be elected to any other voting office of the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pastor of the Local Church</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/the-pastor-of-the-local-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/the-pastor-of-the-local-church/</guid>
      <description>The pastor of the Local Church shall attend all meetings of the board, and shall report at all regular meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honorary Officers</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/honorary-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/honorary-officers/</guid>
      <description>Upon the signed recommendation of one member, seconded by another member, and the three-fourths vote by ballot at the annual meeting, an honorary officer position, bearing an appropriate title, may be conferred upon an adult resident of the City of Chicago who has rendered notable service to the Corporation. An honorary officer shall have none of the obligations of membership in the Corporation, but shall be entitled to all of the privileges except those of making motions, of voting, and of holding any other office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nomination Procedure</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/nomination-procedure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/nomination-procedure/</guid>
      <description>At a regular meeting prior to the annual meeting, the Board of Directors shall elect a Nominating Committee of three members whose duty it shall be to nominate candidates for each office to be filled at the annual meeting. Nominations shall invite a diversity of candidates—both from within and beyond the membership of the Church of the Nazarene—especially women, persons of color, recent college graduates, and residents of the City of Chicago who have suffered under oppression, injustice, violence, poverty, hunger, or disease during their residency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballot Election</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ballot-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ballot-election/</guid>
      <description>Officers shall be elected by ballot, except that when there is only one nominee for an office, the chair shall declare the nominee elected by acclamation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Office</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/terms-of-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/terms-of-office/</guid>
      <description>An officer’s term shall begin at the close of the annual meeting at which the officer is elected. Officers shall serve for a term of one year and until their successors are elected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal From Office</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/removal-from-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/removal-from-office/</guid>
      <description>Officers may be removed from office for cause of disciplinary proceedings as provided in the parliamentary authority. Officers who are also members of the Church of the Nazarene may be removed from office for cause of disciplinary proceedings as provided in the Manual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Holding Limitations</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/office-holding-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/office-holding-limitations/</guid>
      <description>No member shall hold more than one voting office at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>