<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Join Us on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Join Us on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 21:51:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Prayer Walk</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/prayer-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:04:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/prayer-walk/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re invited! Join us as we pray outside landmarks across our neighborhood and the surrounding community areas. Everyday we post times and locations on Twitter and Facebook.
You can also follow along with us on our Google Map.

Sundays—Our Neighborhood Parks Every Sunday we pray at one of the smaller parks in a neighborhood within the Loop Community Area or the Near South Side.
 Printer&amp;rsquo;s Row New East Side Dearborn Park Prairie District and South Loop Chinatown  Mondays—Our Criminal Justice System Every Monday we pray for the inmates of the Metropolitan Correctional Center, their families and visitors, those victimized by crime, and the prison personnel, as well as for healing to our country’s justice system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:04:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/sunday/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re invited! When: Sundays 10:30 a.m.
Where: 633 S Plymouth Ct, #703, Chicago, IL 60605
On Sunday mornings we meet in the home of Reuben and Stephanie Lillie.
Each week we post readings and additional event details on Twitter and Facebook to help you prepare for our time together and to make it easier for you to invite others through social media.
If you can, please let us know ahead of time that you&amp;rsquo;re coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Member of Our Church</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:40:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/membership/</guid>
      <description>Being a member in the Church of the Nazarene makes you part of a global family. And joining LoopNaz offers opportunities to shape our local branch of that family for generations.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in becoming a member, please contact us. Our pastor will personally assist you with any questions you may have while learning more about our history, beliefs, and what to expect as a member in the Church of the Nazarene in Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Compassionate Ministry Partner</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 11:07:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/partnership/</guid>
      <description>Let’s make a difference—together We can do more together than we could ever do apart. And we’re so glad you’re interested in joining with us as a compassionate ministry partner.
We welcome any and all business and organizations who wish to work with us in our mission of compassion to our neighbors in greatest need. And we are eager to volunteer for projects and initiatives through your business or organization too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>