<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News Archives on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News Archives on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 21:44:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks, Elise!</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/thanks-elise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/thanks-elise/</guid>
      <description>Let’s celebrate a job well done!
Thank you Elise Fetzer for your faithful service to LoopNaz. You are a credit to your parents, your home church, and Olivet Nazarene University.
During her last semester break of her last year of college, from December 16, 2018 to January 13, 2019, Elise spent 88 hours over the course of 18 days with us in Chicago as part of her cross-cultural ministry field experience toward her Bachelor of Arts in Intercultural Studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Last Day with LoopNaz</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-last-day-with-loopnaz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-last-day-with-loopnaz/</guid>
      <description>This past Sunday marked the last official day of my field studies experience with the Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries. Like every Sunday, we gathered in the Lillie’s home to reflect upon the passages from the Revised Common Lectionary. This time: Psalm 29, Isaiah 43:1–7, Acts 8:14–17, and Luke 3:15–17; 21–22. Following the church calendar and the passage from Luke, this Sunday also marked our celebration of the baptism of Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Home</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/finding-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/finding-home/</guid>
      <description>Every Friday with LoopNaz we pray for our neighbors who are going through US Citizenship and Immigration Service (USCIS) outside the Chicago Field Office. Any individual residing in Illinois who is going through immigration, citizenship, or asylum processes must come here.
And as I’ve thought about how best to pray for these neighbors, I’ve often been struck how little I can relate to what it’s like to be in their shoes, since I’m as a US citizen by birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning a Corner</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/turning-a-corner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/turning-a-corner/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to believe my four weeks with LoopNaz are near completion. In many ways, it’s like I just started this field experience. But I can hardly say that I will be walking away with the same understanding of the Loop—or LoopNaz for that matter—that I came in with.
This past Thursday had a couple moments that showed me the corner I’ve turned.
Interview at City Hall Starting off the day, Reuben and I got to sit down and have a conversation with Ms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/winter-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/winter-is-here/</guid>
      <description>This past Wednesday marked the coldest day yet in my time downtown with LoopNaz. Overall, the weather really hasn’t been that bad. But Wednesday was the first day while I’ve been in the Loop that it has dropped below 20 degrees.
As it happens, Wednesday is also our longest prayer walk of the week, taking us around the perimeter of the entire CTA Union Loop. So we had a good hour ahead of us in this weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Talk About Public Housing</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/lets-talk-about-public-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 10:58:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/lets-talk-about-public-housing/</guid>
      <description>This past Tuesday, Reuben and I attended “A People’s Forum on Public Housing and Housing Insecurity,” featuring Chicago mayoral candidates running in the upcoming February 2019 election.
Unlike other mayoral forums this election season, this one focused on hearing the lived experiences of Chicago citizens. The basic set up was around five different conversation circles. Each group of people stayed together while the six mayoral candidates took turns sitting in on the circles, moving every fifteen minutes or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Epiphany</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/reflections-on-epiphany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/reflections-on-epiphany/</guid>
      <description>This is probably the first year of my life I’ve ever spent much time reflecting on Epiphany. I know what it is, and I recall other’s ideas about it, perhaps even ones I heard in church. But I don’t remember ever taking much time to consider its significance myself until Sunday.
So, as we spent Sunday’s gathering at the Lillie’s celebrating Epiphany, we not only looked at the coming of the Magi in Matthew 2:1–12, but we also followed the rest of the Revised Common Lectionary readings from Psalm 72:1–14; Isaiah 60:1–6; and Ephesians 3:1–12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Beads</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/prayer-beads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/prayer-beads/</guid>
      <description>The first time Reuben made reference to prayer beads in conversation, I was completely oblivious. It was during my field studies orientation, on our introductory prayer walk. He was talking about how in his own prayers he’s not always known how to pray for the Loop, and he had gestured towards his own set of prayer beads on his wrist.
And although I hadn’t noticed the reference Reuben was actually trying to make in that moment—mostly because I hadn’t been looking at him at the time—and I hadn’t much of an idea of what prayer beads actually were yet, I could relate to the sentiment that Reuben had expressed about not knowing how to pray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Seat at the Table</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/a-seat-at-the-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/a-seat-at-the-table/</guid>
      <description>This past Thursday, I joined Reuben at the Chicago Central District Church of the Nazarene’s monthly pastors’ meeting, called POPS (Pastors on Purpose).
They have a morning devotion, a guest speaker, and then break-out sessions. This month, Pastor Herb Ireland spoke about “Flourishing and Finishing Well as a Nazarene Pastor,” based on his research for how pastor can take better care of themselves in holistic ways. Then we broke up into small group cohorts around tables, with several groups of men and one group of women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Care</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/how-we-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/how-we-care/</guid>
      <description>As I was headed out the door to my bus stop this past Wednesday, I double checked the weather forecast. When I looked, it said nothing about precipitation and it was currently just around 32 degrees Fahrenheit, so I felt like I was dressed fine and didn’t need an umbrella.
Then I stepped outside &amp;hellip; and it was snowing.
But I shrugged it off because it seemed to be fairly light, and I didn’t think it would be much of a bother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Trip to Chinatown</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-first-trip-to-chinatown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-first-trip-to-chinatown/</guid>
      <description>In a history of firsts for me in Chicago, I took my first trip to Chinatown with the Lillie’s after our Sunday gathering at their condo.
Before we headed to Chinatown Square for our daily prayer walk, we took a brief stroll down Wentworth Avenue, which is one of the central streets in Chinatown.
As the Lillie’s and I walked throughout Chinatown, Reuben shared with me some of the background of the neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incarnational Ministry</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/incarnational-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/incarnational-ministry/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned previously, I’m reading four books as part of my field studies with LoopNaz. I recently finished the second book, Ministering Cross-Culturally: An Incarnational Model for Personal Relationships by Sherwood G. Lingenfelter and Marvin K. Mayers.
As the title suggests, the book offers a guide for how to live incarnationally in cross-cultural ministry. For the authors, that means taking Jesus’s life as the primary example.
In particular, Leigenfelter highlights how Christ lived out incarnational ministry not by immersing himself in the world of humanity generally speaking, but specifically that he came as a Jew in ancient Israel-Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hostel Vibes</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/hostel-vibes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/hostel-vibes/</guid>
      <description>From Wednesday to Thursday I spent my first night in Chicago. This is yet another reminder that I’m not as familiar with the city as I once thought. Given that there have been several times I’ve told people that I’m basically from Chicago (since it’s often an easier association than Oak Lawn), you’d think I’d have slept at least one night in the city before this week.
I spent the night at the HI (Hosteling International) Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spaces We Inhabit</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-spaces-we-inhabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-spaces-we-inhabit/</guid>
      <description>In addition to spending time with LoopNaz, I&amp;rsquo;m also reading four books as part of my cross-cultural ministry field studies. My first book was Mark Batterson’s The Circle Maker (2011). Batterson focuses a lot on the importance and value of prayer walks, particularly through the spaces that we inhabit and care for.
There is a certain tangibility to the practice of actively walking through and praying for the spaces that we are bringing before God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering at Pacific Garden Mission</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/volunteering-at-pacific-garden-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 08:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/volunteering-at-pacific-garden-mission/</guid>
      <description>Reuben, Corban, and I arrived for our day of volunteering at Pacific Garden Mission (PGM) just a few minutes before 9 a.m. It took us a moment, but eventually we found the proper door where a staff member was eager to greet us.
For those of you who don’t know, PGM is a homeless shelter providing overnight housing and food on a day-by-day basis since 1877. PGM also has four residency programs to assist individuals willing to make longer-term commitments; NewDay (for those who’ve struggled with substance abuse); New Life (for spiritual and workforce development); Mothers and Children’s Ministry; and the Transient Resident Program (a 60-day trial period with options for extensions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ‘L’ongest Day Yet</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-longest-day-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 09:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-longest-day-yet/</guid>
      <description>“Let’s ride the whole ‘L’ in one day,” they said. “It’ll be fun,” they said.
When Reuben asked me about a month ago if I wanted to ride the whole ‘L’ in a day for this cross-cultural field experience, I thought, “Yeah, that should be interesting.” It sounded like a good way to explore and see the city of Chicago, right?
Well, I didn’t totally know what I was in for (although, Reuben did try to warn me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>For my work with LoopNaz, I’ve been commuting downtown using public transportation. Now, while I’ve genuinely appreciated the availability of public transportation—especially since I don’t have a car—I’ve also had to cope with the frustration of delays and less frequent buses or trains. Sometimes, I just wish the commuting process on public transit could be more expedient.
In the midst of these frankly minor inconveniences, however, I’ve had some humbling reminders that I have it pretty easy—as an able-bodied person, that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion, Gathering, and Prayer Reflection</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday, I participated in my first Sunday gathering with the Lillie family as part of my downtown experience with LoopNaz.
Reuben greeted me decked out in a pink checkered shirt and a Green Bay Packer’s jersey. This moment itself should probably qualify as a cross-cultural moment, given the proximity of a die-hard Packer’s fan originally from Pennsylvania living in Chicago—blocks from Soldier Field—who is also married to a die-hard Bear’s fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation: Check?</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</guid>
      <description>This past Saturday was my orientation with the Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries. For the majority of this orientation, Reuben and I spent a good three or so hours that afternoon walking around the northern portion of the Loop, in theory to get me better acquainted with the area.
However, the term orientation might be a bit misleading. Rather than feeling like I gained any reasonable acquaintance with the neighborhood, I realized just how much I don’t know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>