<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 21:44:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion, Gathering, and Prayer Reflection</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday, I participated in my first Sunday gathering with the Lillie family as part of my downtown experience with LoopNaz.
Reuben greeted me decked out in a pink checkered shirt and a Packer’s jersey. This moment itself should probably qualify as a cross-cultural moment, given the proximity of a die-hard Green Bay Packer’s originally fan from Pennsylvania living in Chicago—blocks from Soldier Field—who is also married to a die-hard Bear’s fan (For those of you who don’t know, I am fulfilling this field experience with LoopNaz, specifically for a cross-cultural ministry course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation: Check?</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</guid>
      <description>This past Saturday was my orientation with the Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries. For the majority of this orientation, Reuben and I spent a good three or so hours that afternoon walking around the northern portion of the Loop, in theory to get me better acquainted with the area.
However, the term orientation might be a bit misleading. Rather than feeling like I gained any reasonable acquaintance with the neighborhood, I realized just how much I don’t know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>