<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 21:44:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>For my work with LoopNaz, I’ve been commuting downtown using public transportation. Now, while I’ve genuinely appreciated the availability of public transportation—especially since I don’t have a car—I’ve also had to cope with the frustration of delays and less frequent buses or trains. Sometimes, I just wish the commuting process on public transit could be more expedient.
In the midst of these frankly minor inconveniences, however, I’ve had some humbling reminders that I have it pretty easy—as an able-bodied person, that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion, Gathering, and Prayer Reflection</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday, I participated in my first Sunday gathering with the Lillie family as part of my downtown experience with LoopNaz.
Reuben greeted me decked out in a pink checkered shirt and a Green Bay Packer’s jersey. This moment itself should probably qualify as a cross-cultural moment, given the proximity of a die-hard Packer’s fan originally from Pennsylvania living in Chicago—blocks from Soldier Field—who is also married to a die-hard Bear’s fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation: Check?</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</guid>
      <description>This past Saturday was my orientation with the Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries. For the majority of this orientation, Reuben and I spent a good three or so hours that afternoon walking around the northern portion of the Loop, in theory to get me better acquainted with the area.
However, the term orientation might be a bit misleading. Rather than feeling like I gained any reasonable acquaintance with the neighborhood, I realized just how much I don’t know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>