<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 21:44:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Trip to Chinatown</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-first-trip-to-chinatown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-first-trip-to-chinatown/</guid>
      <description>In a history of firsts for me in Chicago, I took my first trip to Chinatown with the Lillie’s after our Sunday gathering at their condo.
Before we headed to Chinatown Square for our daily prayer walk, we took a brief stroll down Wentworth Avenue, which is one of the central streets in Chinatown.
As the Lillie’s and I walked throughout Chinatown, Reuben shared with me some of the background of the neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incarnational Ministry</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/incarnational-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/incarnational-ministry/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned previously, I’m reading four books as part of my field studies with LoopNaz. I recently finished the second book, Ministering Cross-Culturally: An Incarnational Model for Personal Relationships by Sherwood G. Lingenfelter and Marvin K. Mayers.
As the title suggests, the book offers a guide for how to live incarnationally in cross-cultural ministry. For the authors, that means taking Jesus’s life as the primary example.
In particular, Leigenfelter highlights how Christ lived out incarnational ministry not by immersing himself in the world of humanity generally speaking, but specifically that he came as a Jew in ancient Israel-Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hostel Vibes</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/hostel-vibes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/hostel-vibes/</guid>
      <description>From Wednesday to Thursday I spent my first night in Chicago. This is yet another reminder that I’m not as familiar with the city as I once thought. Given that there have been several times I’ve told people that I’m basically from Chicago (since it’s often an easier association than Oak Lawn), you’d think I’d have slept at least one night in the city before this week.
I spent the night at the HI (Hosteling International) Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spaces We Inhabit</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-spaces-we-inhabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-spaces-we-inhabit/</guid>
      <description>In addition to spending time with LoopNaz, I&amp;rsquo;m also reading four books as part of my cross-cultural ministry field studies. My first book was Mark Batterson’s The Circle Maker (2011). Batterson focuses a lot on the importance and value of prayer walks, particularly through the spaces that we inhabit and care for.
There is a certain tangibility to the practice of actively walking through and praying for the spaces that we are bringing before God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering at Pacific Garden Mission</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/volunteering-at-pacific-garden-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 08:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/volunteering-at-pacific-garden-mission/</guid>
      <description>Reuben, Corban, and I arrived for our day of volunteering at Pacific Garden Mission (PGM) just a few minutes before 9 a.m. It took us a moment, but eventually we found the proper door where a staff member was eager to greet us.
For those of you who don’t know, PGM is a homeless shelter providing overnight housing and food on a day-by-day basis since 1877. PGM also has four residency programs to assist individuals willing to make longer-term commitments; NewDay (for those who’ve struggled with substance abuse); New Life (for spiritual and workforce development); Mothers and Children’s Ministry; and the Transient Resident Program (a 60-day trial period with options for extensions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ‘L’ongest Day Yet</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-longest-day-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 09:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-longest-day-yet/</guid>
      <description>“Let’s ride the whole ‘L’ in one day,” they said. “It’ll be fun,” they said.
When Reuben asked me about a month ago if I wanted to ride the whole ‘L’ in a day for this cross-cultural field experience, I thought, “Yeah, that should be interesting.” It sounded like a good way to explore and see the city of Chicago, right?
Well, I didn’t totally know what I was in for (although, Reuben did try to warn me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>For my work with LoopNaz, I’ve been commuting downtown using public transportation. Now, while I’ve genuinely appreciated the availability of public transportation—especially since I don’t have a car—I’ve also had to cope with the frustration of delays and less frequent buses or trains. Sometimes, I just wish the commuting process on public transit could be more expedient.
In the midst of these frankly minor inconveniences, however, I’ve had some humbling reminders that I have it pretty easy—as an able-bodied person, that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion, Gathering, and Prayer Reflection</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday, I participated in my first Sunday gathering with the Lillie family as part of my downtown experience with LoopNaz.
Reuben greeted me decked out in a pink checkered shirt and a Green Bay Packer’s jersey. This moment itself should probably qualify as a cross-cultural moment, given the proximity of a die-hard Packer’s fan originally from Pennsylvania living in Chicago—blocks from Soldier Field—who is also married to a die-hard Bear’s fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation: Check?</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</guid>
      <description>This past Saturday was my orientation with the Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries. For the majority of this orientation, Reuben and I spent a good three or so hours that afternoon walking around the northern portion of the Loop, in theory to get me better acquainted with the area.
However, the term orientation might be a bit misleading. Rather than feeling like I gained any reasonable acquaintance with the neighborhood, I realized just how much I don’t know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>