<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Us on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Us on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 21:51:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Story</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/story/</guid>
      <description>The Loop Church of the Nazarene may have taken seed in 2018, but our church’s roots in Chicago reach back as far as 1900.
From those initial meetings in the Philpot’s home over a century ago, to opening the Southside Pentecostal Mission in 1903, to the tent meeting in 1904 that became Chicago First, to hosting the First General Assembly in 1907—the legacy of Nazarenes in Chicago is rich and inspiring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Mission</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:01:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/mission/</guid>
      <description>Your actions reveal what you actually believe. Anything worth believing is worth doing. This simple truth is the hallmark of any vital faith. And it&amp;rsquo;s the heartbeat of the Church of the Nazarene and Nazarene Compassionate Ministries.
 The Mission of the International Church of the Nazarene   to make Christlike disciples in the nations
The Church of the Nazarene
 As Nazarenes, we&amp;rsquo;re convinced that discipleship doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen—in fact, it can’t happen without compassion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Values</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/values/</guid>
      <description>We Pray When we say “we pray”—we mean it.
Prayer is our highest priority and our primary method for engaging our neighbors.
Everything we do begins and ends and comes out of our response through prayer.
We take a daily prayer walk around our community outside points of interest like government buildings, schools, train stations, and parks. Whether you’re in the Loop often or this is your first time, we’re here to pray with you and for you and for our neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Vision</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/vision/</guid>
      <description>Any vision we cast must help us chart a path from our mission and values.
Let’s run with this: We pray, we care, and we share to meet our neighbors’ immediate and long-term physical and spiritual needs in personable and sustainable ways.
This vision ensures that our mission of discipleship begins and ends with compassion. 1 John 4:19 serves as a striking reminder and challenge: “We love because God first loved us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Leadership</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/leadership/</guid>
      <description>Our Pastor  Reuben L. Lillie   In July 2018, Reuben and his family accepted the call to establish the Loop Church of the Nazarene in downtown Chicago. This marks the first official presence of the Church of the Nazarene here since 1906. And, with the organization of the Loop Nazarene Compassionate Ministries, Inc. on Octboer 13, 2018, “LoopNaz” (for short) became the first ever Nazarene Compassionate Ministry center in Chicago city limits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>