<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Board of Directors on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Board of Directors on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:53:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Composition</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-composition/</guid>
      <description>The officers of the Corporation, including the Directors, shall constitute the Board of Directors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Duties and Powers</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-duties-and-powers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-duties-and-powers/</guid>
      <description>The Board of Directors shall have full power and authority over the affairs of the Corporation, and shall perform such duties as are specified in these bylaws and in partnership with the Local Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Membership Dues</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-membership-dues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:53:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-membership-dues/</guid>
      <description>Annual dues shall be in a cash amount of a member’s own choosing greater than zero dollars, agreed upon through a written pledge to be submitted to the Treasurer on or before the date of the second regular meeting of the year. Dues shall be payable in advance on or before the date of the final regular meeting prior to the annual meeting. The Treasurer shall notify members 30 days in arrears, and those whose dues are not paid on or before the date of the annual meeting shall not be eligible to serve on the Board of Directors for the following year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensation</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/compensation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/compensation/</guid>
      <description>Members of the Board of Directors shall not receive any compensation for their services as Directors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>