<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 14:31:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditions to Amend Bylaws</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/amendment-of-bylaws/conditions-to-amend-bylaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:56:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/amendment-of-bylaws/conditions-to-amend-bylaws/</guid>
      <description>The bylaws may be amended at any regular meeting of the Corporation by a two-thirds vote, provided that the amendment has been submitted in writing at the previous regular meeting or at a special meeting called for the purpose of submitting such an amendment for consideration at the next regular meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance Committee</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/finance-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/finance-committee/</guid>
      <description>The chair shall appoint a Finance Committee composed of the Treasurer and two other members promptly after the annual meeting. This committee shall prepare a budget for the administrative year and submit it to the Corporation on or before the day of the first regular meeting. This committee may from time to time submit amendments to the budget for the current administrative year, which may be adopted by a majority vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Composition</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-composition/</guid>
      <description>The officers of the Corporation, including the Directors, shall constitute the Board of Directors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Meetings</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/regular-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:53:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/regular-meetings/</guid>
      <description>The regular meetings of the Corporation shall be held quarterly at a time and place designated by the chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officers and Duties</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/officers-and-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/officers-and-duties/</guid>
      <description>The officers of the Corporation shall be a Board Chairperson; a Secretary; a Treasurer; no fewer than two and as many as twenty-two Directors; plus any and all Honorary Officers. These officers shall perform the duties prescribed by these bylaws and by the parliamentary authority adopted by the Corporation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:49:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/registration/</guid>
      <description>The Corporation shall be a registered Nazarene Compassionate Ministry Center through the Loop Church of the Nazarene (Local Church) as provided in the current edition of the Manual of the Church of the Nazarene (Manual).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Prayer Walk</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/prayer-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:04:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/prayer-walk/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re invited! Join us as we pray outside landmarks across our neighborhood and the surrounding community areas. Everyday we post times and locations on Twitter and Facebook.
You can also follow along with us on our Google Map.
 A Google Map marking our daily prayer walk locations. Click the map to view an interactive version in a separate tab.
  Sundays—Our Neighborhood Parks Every Sunday we pray at one of the smaller parks in a neighborhood within the Loop Community Area or the Near South Side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Story</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/story/</guid>
      <description>The Loop Church of the Nazarene may have taken seed in 2018, but our church’s roots in Chicago reach back as far as 1900.
From those initial meetings in the Philpot’s home over a century ago, to opening the Southside Pentecostal Mission in 1903, to the tent meeting in 1904 that became Chicago First, to hosting the First General Assembly in 1907—the legacy of Nazarenes in Chicago is rich and inspiring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compulsory Amendments</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/amendment-of-bylaws/compulsory-amendments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/amendment-of-bylaws/compulsory-amendments/</guid>
      <description>Any amendment to these bylaws necessitated by amendments to the Manual shall be effected by the Board of Directors and reported in writing to the district in jurisdiction of the Local Church within sixty days following the adoption of such amendments by the Church of the Nazarene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditing Committee</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/auditing-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/auditing-committee/</guid>
      <description>The chair shall appoint an Auditing Committee of three members at a regular meeting prior to the annual meeting, whose duty it shall be to audit the Treasurer’s accounts at the close of the administrative year and to report at the annual meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Duties and Powers</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-duties-and-powers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-duties-and-powers/</guid>
      <description>The Board of Directors shall have full power and authority over the affairs of the Corporation, and shall perform such duties as are specified in these bylaws and in partnership with the Local Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Meetings</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/annual-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:53:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/annual-meetings/</guid>
      <description>The regular meeting during the final quarter of the administrative year shall be known as the annual meeting and shall be for the purposes of electing officers; receiving reports of officers and committees; and any other business that may arise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Chairperson</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/board-chairperson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/board-chairperson/</guid>
      <description>If the office of Board Chairperson should become vacant between elections, then the Secretary shall preside until the immediate election of a chairperson pro tem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle Office</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/principle-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/principle-office/</guid>
      <description>In partnership with the Local Church, the Corporation shall operate within the community area of the City of Chicago officially recognized as “the Loop.” The Corporation may acquire additional space and offer additional services outside the Loop, provided that the principal office of the Corporation remains within the Loop and that the Corporation continues to offer compassionate ministry services in the Loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:04:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/sunday/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re invited! When: Sundays 10:30 a.m.
Where: 633 S Plymouth Ct, #703, Chicago, IL 60605
On Sunday mornings we meet in the home of Reuben and Stephanie Lillie.
Each week we post readings and additional event details on Twitter and Facebook to help you prepare for our time together and to make it easier for you to invite others through social media.
If you can, please let us know ahead of time that you&amp;rsquo;re coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Mission</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:01:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/mission/</guid>
      <description>Your actions reveal what you actually believe. Anything worth believing is worth doing. This simple truth is the hallmark of any vital faith. And it&amp;rsquo;s the heartbeat of the Church of the Nazarene and Nazarene Compassionate Ministries.
 The Mission of the International Church of the Nazarene   to make Christlike disciples in the nations
The Church of the Nazarene
 As Nazarenes, we&amp;rsquo;re convinced that discipleship doesn&amp;rsquo;t just happen—in fact, it can’t happen without compassion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Membership Dues</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-membership-dues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 20:53:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/board-membership-dues/</guid>
      <description>Annual dues shall be in a cash amount of a member’s own choosing greater than zero dollars, agreed upon through a written pledge to be submitted to the Treasurer on or before the date of the second regular meeting of the year. Dues shall be payable in advance on or before the date of the final regular meeting prior to the annual meeting. The Treasurer shall notify members 30 days in arrears, and those whose dues are not paid on or before the date of the annual meeting shall not be eligible to serve on the Board of Directors for the following year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Committees</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/other-committees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/other-committees/</guid>
      <description>The Corporation may establish other committees, standing or special, as it shall from time to time deem necessary to carry on the work of the Corporation. The chair shall appoint their members, except that in the absence of the chair, the Board of Directors may appoint the members of a special committee, who shall be treated as though appointed by the chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Meetings</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/special-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:53:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/special-meetings/</guid>
      <description>A special meeting may be called by the chair or by a written request of three members of the Board of Directors. The purpose of the meeting shall be stated in the call, which shall be communicated to all members at least 48 hours before the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasurer</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/treasurer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/treasurer/</guid>
      <description>The Treasurer may not be related by blood, marriage, or domestic partnership within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity to any officer of the Corporation or corporate staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/property/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:50:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/property/</guid>
      <description>If the Corporation should wish to dissolve; or should relocate or attempt to relocate its principal office outside the Loop, or otherwise cease to offer all or most of its compassionate ministry services within the Loop; or in the event of its withdrawal or attempted withdrawal from its partnership with the Church of the Nazarene, then any property of the Corporation that may exist shall in no way be diverted to other purposes, but title shall pass to the Local Church acting as agent for the Corporation, or other authorized agents, for the use of the Local Church at large, as its board shall direct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Member of Our Church</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:40:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/membership/</guid>
      <description>Being a member in the Church of the Nazarene makes you part of a global family. And joining LoopNaz offers opportunities to shape our local branch of that family for generations.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in becoming a member, please contact us. Our pastor will personally assist you with any questions you may have while learning more about our history, beliefs, and what to expect as a member in the Church of the Nazarene in Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Values</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/values/</guid>
      <description>We Pray When we say “we pray”—we mean it.
Prayer is our highest priority and our primary method for engaging our neighbors.
Everything we do begins and ends and comes out of our response through prayer.
We take a daily prayer walk around our community outside points of interest like government buildings, schools, train stations, and parks. Whether you’re in the Loop often or this is your first time, we’re here to pray with you and for you and for our neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ex Officio Committee Membership</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/ex-officio-committee-membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/committees/ex-officio-committee-membership/</guid>
      <description>The chair shall be ex officio a member of all committees except the Nominating Committee and all disciplinary committees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensation</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/compensation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:55:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/board-of-directors/compensation/</guid>
      <description>Members of the Board of Directors shall not receive any compensation for their services as Directors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Year</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/administrative-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/administrative-year/</guid>
      <description>The administrative year of the Corporation shall run concurrently with the administrative year of the Local Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ex Officio Officers</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ex-officio-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ex-officio-officers/</guid>
      <description>The following persons shall be ex officio members of the Board of Directors:
 The pastor of the Local Church The district superintendent in jurisdiction of the Local Church The Regional Director of Nazarene Compassionate Ministries The President of Olivet Nazarene University The Mayor of the City of Chicago The aldermen of any and all wards of the City of Chicago whose boundaries lie within the Loop The commissioners of any and all districts of Cook County whose boundaries lie within the Loop  Except for the pastor of the Local Church, no ex officio member may be elected to any other voting office of the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Compassionate Ministry Partner</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/join/partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 11:07:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/join/partnership/</guid>
      <description>Let’s make a difference—together We can do more together than we could ever do apart. And we’re so glad you’re interested in joining with us as a compassionate ministry partner.
We welcome any and all business and organizations who wish to work with us in our mission of compassion to our neighbors in greatest need. And we are eager to volunteer for projects and initiatives through your business or organization too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Vision</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/vision/</guid>
      <description>Any vision we cast must help us chart a path from our mission and values.
Let’s run with this: We pray, we care, and we share to meet our neighbors’ immediate and long-term physical and spiritual needs in personable and sustainable ways.
This vision ensures that our mission of discipleship begins and ends with compassion. 1 John 4:19 serves as a striking reminder and challenge: “We love because God first loved us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notice of Meetings</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/notice-of-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/notice-of-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Official notice of each regular meeting shall be given to each member by email not less than fifteen days prior to the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pastor of the Local Church</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/the-pastor-of-the-local-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/the-pastor-of-the-local-church/</guid>
      <description>The pastor of the Local Church shall attend all meetings of the board, and shall report at all regular meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Leadership</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/about/leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:03:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/about/leadership/</guid>
      <description>Our Pastor  Reuben L. Lillie   In July 2018, Reuben and his family accepted the call to establish the Loop Church of the Nazarene in downtown Chicago. This marks the first official presence of the Church of the Nazarene here since 1906. And, with the organization of the Loop Nazarene Compassionate Ministries, Inc. on October 13, 2018, “LoopNaz” (for short) became the first ever Nazarene Compassionate Ministry center in Chicago city limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quorum</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/quorum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:54:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/meetings/quorum/</guid>
      <description>Three voting members of the Board of Directors shall constitute a quorum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honorary Officers</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/honorary-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:51:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/honorary-officers/</guid>
      <description>Upon the signed recommendation of one member, seconded by another member, and the three-fourths vote by ballot at the annual meeting, an honorary officer position, bearing an appropriate title, may be conferred upon an adult resident of the City of Chicago who has rendered notable service to the Corporation. An honorary officer shall have none of the obligations of membership in the Corporation, but shall be entitled to all of the privileges except those of making motions, of voting, and of holding any other office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nomination Procedure</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/nomination-procedure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/nomination-procedure/</guid>
      <description>At a regular meeting prior to the annual meeting, the Board of Directors shall elect a Nominating Committee of three members whose duty it shall be to nominate candidates for each office to be filled at the annual meeting. Nominations shall invite a diversity of candidates—both from within and beyond the membership of the Church of the Nazarene—especially women, persons of color, recent college graduates, and residents of the City of Chicago who have suffered under oppression, injustice, violence, poverty, hunger, or disease during their residency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballot Election</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ballot-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/ballot-election/</guid>
      <description>Officers shall be elected by ballot, except that when there is only one nominee for an office, the chair shall declare the nominee elected by acclamation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Office</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/terms-of-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/terms-of-office/</guid>
      <description>An officer’s term shall begin at the close of the annual meeting at which the officer is elected. Officers shall serve for a term of one year and until their successors are elected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal From Office</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/removal-from-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/removal-from-office/</guid>
      <description>Officers may be removed from office for cause of disciplinary proceedings as provided in the parliamentary authority. Officers who are also members of the Church of the Nazarene may be removed from office for cause of disciplinary proceedings as provided in the Manual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Holding Limitations</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/office-holding-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:52:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/officers/office-holding-limitations/</guid>
      <description>No member shall hold more than one voting office at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Epiphany</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/reflections-on-epiphany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/reflections-on-epiphany/</guid>
      <description>This is probably the first year of my life I’ve ever spent much time reflecting on Epiphany. I know what it is, and I recall other’s ideas about it, perhaps even ones I heard in church. But I don’t remember ever taking much time to consider its significance myself until Sunday.
So, as we spent Sunday’s gathering at the Lillie’s celebrating Epiphany, we not only looked at the coming of the Magi in Matthew 2:1–12, but we also followed the rest of the Revised Common Lectionary readings from Psalm 72:1–14; Isaiah 60:1–6; and Ephesians 3:1–12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Beads</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/prayer-beads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/prayer-beads/</guid>
      <description>The first time Reuben made reference to prayer beads in conversation, I was completely oblivious. It was during my field studies orientation, on our introductory prayer walk. He was talking about how in his own prayers he’s not always known how to pray for the Loop, and he had gestured towards his own set of prayer beads on his wrist.
And although I hadn’t noticed the reference Reuben was actually trying to make in that moment—mostly because I hadn’t been looking at him at the time—and I hadn’t much of an idea of what prayer beads actually were yet, I could relate to the sentiment that Reuben had expressed about not knowing how to pray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Seat at the Table</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/a-seat-at-the-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/a-seat-at-the-table/</guid>
      <description>This past Thursday, I joined Reuben at the Chicago Central District Church of the Nazarene’s monthly pastors’ meeting, called POPS (Pastors on Purpose).
They have a morning devotion, a guest speaker, and then break-out sessions. This month, Pastor Herb Ireland spoke about “Flourishing and Finishing Well as a Nazarene Pastor,” based on his research for how pastor can take better care of themselves in holistic ways. Then we broke up into small group cohorts around tables, with several groups of men and one group of women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Care</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/how-we-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/how-we-care/</guid>
      <description>As I was headed out the door to my bus stop this past Wednesday, I double checked the weather forecast. When I looked, it said nothing about precipitation and it was currently just around 32 degrees Fahrenheit, so I felt like I was dressed fine and didn’t need an umbrella.
Then I stepped outside &amp;hellip; and it was snowing.
But I shrugged it off because it seemed to be fairly light, and I didn’t think it would be much of a bother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Trip to Chinatown</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-first-trip-to-chinatown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2019/01/my-first-trip-to-chinatown/</guid>
      <description>In a history of firsts for me in Chicago, I took my first trip to Chinatown with the Lillie’s after our Sunday gathering at their condo.
Before we headed to Chinatown Square for our daily prayer walk, we took a brief stroll down Wentworth Avenue, which is one of the central streets in Chinatown.
As the Lillie’s and I walked throughout Chinatown, Reuben shared with me some of the background of the neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incarnational Ministry</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/incarnational-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/incarnational-ministry/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned previously, I’m reading four books as part of my field studies with LoopNaz. I recently finished the second book, Ministering Cross-Culturally: An Incarnational Model for Personal Relationships by Sherwood G. Lingenfelter and Marvin K. Mayers.
As the title suggests, the book offers a guide for how to live incarnationally in cross-cultural ministry. For the authors, that means taking Jesus’s life as the primary example.
In particular, Leigenfelter highlights how Christ lived out incarnational ministry not by immersing himself in the world of humanity generally speaking, but specifically that he came as a Jew in ancient Israel-Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hostel Vibes</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/hostel-vibes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/hostel-vibes/</guid>
      <description>From Wednesday to Thursday I spent my first night in Chicago. This is yet another reminder that I’m not as familiar with the city as I once thought. Given that there have been several times I’ve told people that I’m basically from Chicago (since it’s often an easier association than Oak Lawn), you’d think I’d have slept at least one night in the city before this week.
I spent the night at the HI (Hosteling International) Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spaces We Inhabit</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-spaces-we-inhabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-spaces-we-inhabit/</guid>
      <description>In addition to spending time with LoopNaz, I&amp;rsquo;m also reading four books as part of my cross-cultural ministry field studies. My first book was Mark Batterson’s The Circle Maker (2011). Batterson focuses a lot on the importance and value of prayer walks, particularly through the spaces that we inhabit and care for.
There is a certain tangibility to the practice of actively walking through and praying for the spaces that we are bringing before God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering at Pacific Garden Mission</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/volunteering-at-pacific-garden-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 08:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/volunteering-at-pacific-garden-mission/</guid>
      <description>Reuben, Corban, and I arrived for our day of volunteering at Pacific Garden Mission (PGM) just a few minutes before 9 a.m. It took us a moment, but eventually we found the proper door where a staff member was eager to greet us.
For those of you who don’t know, PGM is a homeless shelter providing overnight housing and food on a day-by-day basis since 1877. PGM also has four residency programs to assist individuals willing to make longer-term commitments; NewDay (for those who’ve struggled with substance abuse); New Life (for spiritual and workforce development); Mothers and Children’s Ministry; and the Transient Resident Program (a 60-day trial period with options for extensions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ‘L’ongest Day Yet</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-longest-day-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 09:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/the-longest-day-yet/</guid>
      <description>“Let’s ride the whole ‘L’ in one day,” they said. “It’ll be fun,” they said.
When Reuben asked me about a month ago if I wanted to ride the whole ‘L’ in a day for this cross-cultural field experience, I thought, “Yeah, that should be interesting.” It sounded like a good way to explore and see the city of Chicago, right?
Well, I didn’t totally know what I was in for (although, Reuben did try to warn me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/thoughts-on-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>For my work with LoopNaz, I’ve been commuting downtown using public transportation. Now, while I’ve genuinely appreciated the availability of public transportation—especially since I don’t have a car—I’ve also had to cope with the frustration of delays and less frequent buses or trains. Sometimes, I just wish the commuting process on public transit could be more expedient.
In the midst of these frankly minor inconveniences, however, I’ve had some humbling reminders that I have it pretty easy—as an able-bodied person, that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion, Gathering, and Prayer Reflection</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 21:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/communion-gathering-and-prayer-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday, I participated in my first Sunday gathering with the Lillie family as part of my downtown experience with LoopNaz.
Reuben greeted me decked out in a pink checkered shirt and a Green Bay Packer’s jersey. This moment itself should probably qualify as a cross-cultural moment, given the proximity of a die-hard Packer’s fan originally from Pennsylvania living in Chicago—blocks from Soldier Field—who is also married to a die-hard Bear’s fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation: Check?</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/2018/12/orientation-check/</guid>
      <description>This past Saturday was my orientation with the Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries. For the majority of this orientation, Reuben and I spent a good three or so hours that afternoon walking around the northern portion of the Loop, in theory to get me better acquainted with the area.
However, the term orientation might be a bit misleading. Rather than feeling like I gained any reasonable acquaintance with the neighborhood, I realized just how much I don’t know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion with LoopNaz</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/communion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 23:37:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/communion/</guid>
      <description>Come and Dine We offer communion every Sunday.
In the Church of the Nazarene, we believe this meal is a sacrament—a holy encounter with God—proclaiming Jesus’s life, sufferings, death, resurrection, and the hope of Christ’s coming again.
We acknowledge God’s presence among us in a special way each time we celebrate the Lord’s Supper. We also desire to remember anew the death Jesus endured. And we receive afresh the life into which Christ’s Holy Spirit calls us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trademark</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/trademark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 11:32:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/trademark/</guid>
      <description>Trademarks are words, graphic designs, or other indicia that identify the source of a product or service. The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries (collectively, “LoopNaz”) use a variety of trademarks.
The logo; name(s) “The Loop Church of the Nazarene” and “The Loop Nazarene Compassionate Ministries”; and moniker “LoopNaz” are trademarked by the Loop Church of the Nazarene. Please feel free to use our logo for any of the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 14:15:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/colophon/</guid>
      <description>Developed and designed by Reuben L. Lillie
Hosted with GitHub pages
Built using Hugo and Vim on Ubuntu 18.04
Typeset with Raleway font family
Colors and idicia inspired by the City of Chicago and the Chicago Transit Authority
Custom maps created using Google My Maps
Images optimized with Kraken</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 19:01:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Effective as of November 25, 2018
As used in this policy, “personal information” means information that would allow someone to identify you, including your name, email address, IP address, or other information from which someone could deduce your identity.
The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries (collectively “LoopNaz”) receive and use personal information in the following ways:
Website analytics: When you visit our Websites and use our Services, LoopNaz collects some information about your activities through tools such as Google Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Use</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 19:01:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/terms/</guid>
      <description>Effective as of November 25, 2018
General Information Terminology: Welcome, and thank you for your interest in The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries (“The Loop Church of the Nazarene,” “The Loop Nazarene Compassionate Ministries, Inc.,” LoopNaz,” “we,” “our,” or “us”). Unless otherwise noted on a particular site or service, these terms of use (“Terms”) apply to your use of all of the websites that LoopNaz operates. These include https://loopnaz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you for Contacting Us</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 13:28:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Your message has been sent successfully.
We&amp;rsquo;ll respond soon.
Make a Gift
Go to the home page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Us</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:01:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/support/</guid>
      <description>Support LoopNaz Make a Gift
Your gift to LoopNaz can change someone’s life for good.
Please help us help our neighbors in greatest need.
Thanks to our friends at the Chicago Central District Ministry Center, we’re able to offer this secure online giving option while we finish developing our own online giving platform.
Click here to give now toward the Loop Church of the Nazarene.
 Under “Designation,” select “LoopNaz.” For now, if you wish to designate your gift specifically to the Loop Nazarene Compassionate Ministries, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:00:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Your name Your email Your message  Send    Connect with Us on Social</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>