<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Partnership with the Church of the Nazarene on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</title>
    <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Partnership with the Church of the Nazarene on The Loop Church of the Nazarene and Compassionate Ministries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 by The Loop Church of the Nazarene</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:50:07 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:49:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/registration/</guid>
      <description>The Corporation shall be a registered Nazarene Compassionate Ministry Center through the Loop Church of the Nazarene (Local Church) as provided in the current edition of the Manual of the Church of the Nazarene (Manual).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle Office</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/principle-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/principle-office/</guid>
      <description>In partnership with the Local Church, the Corporation shall operate within the community area of the City of Chicago officially recognized as “the Loop.” The Corporation may acquire additional space and offer additional services outside the Loop, provided that the principal office of the Corporation remains within the Loop and that the Corporation continues to offer compassionate ministry services in the Loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property</title>
      <link>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/property/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 18:50:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loopnaz.org/bylaws/partnership-with-the-church-of-the-nazarene/property/</guid>
      <description>If the Corporation should wish to dissolve; or should relocate or attempt to relocate its principal office outside the Loop, or otherwise cease to offer all or most of its compassionate ministry services within the Loop; or in the event of its withdrawal or attempted withdrawal from its partnership with the Church of the Nazarene, then any property of the Corporation that may exist shall in no way be diverted to other purposes, but title shall pass to the Local Church acting as agent for the Corporation, or other authorized agents, for the use of the Local Church at large, as its board shall direct.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>